All right, so let's take
حسناَ، دعونا نأخذ
four subjects that obviously go together:
أربعة مواضيع أربعة تأتي من الواضح معا:
big data, tattoos, immortality and the Greeks.
البيانات الكبيرة، والوشم والخلود والإغريق.
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
Now, the issue about tattoos is that,
الآن، المسألة حول الوشم هي،
without a word, tattoos really do shout.
بدون كلمة، الاوشام حقاً تصرخ.
[Beautiful]
[جميلة]
[Intriguing]
[مثيرة]
So you don't have to say a lot.
لذا لا يجب عليك أن تقول الكثير.
[Allegiance]
[الولاء]
[Very intimate]
[حميمة جداً]
[Serious mistakes]
[أخطاء فادحه]
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And tattoos tell you a lot of stories.
والاوشام تقول لكم الكثير من القصص.
If I can ask an indiscreet question,
إذا أمكنني أن أسال سؤالا أحمق،
how many of you have tattoos?
كم شخص منكم لديه اوشام؟
A few, but not most.
عدد قليل، ولكن معظمكم لا.
What happens if Facebook, Google, Twitter, LinkedIn,
ماذا يحدث لو الفيسبوك، جوجل، تويتر، لينكدين،
cell phones, GPS, Foursquare, Yelp, Travel Advisor,
الهواتف المحمولة، تحديد المواقع، فورزسكوير، يلب، ترافل ادفازير،
all these things you deal with every day
كل هذه الأشياء التي تتعامل معها كل يوم
turn out to be electronic tattoos?
هي في الحقيقة اوشام الإلكترونية؟
And what if they provide as much information
وماذا لو أنها توفر قدر من المعلومات
about who and what you are as any tattoo ever would?
عن من و ما هو انت مثل مايفعل أي وشم؟
What's ended up happening over the past few decades
ما حدث على مدى العقود القليلة الماضية
is the kind of coverage that you had as a head of state
هو نوع التغطية التي تحصل عليها كرئيس دولة
or as a great celebrity
أو كأحد المشاهير
is now being applied to you every day by all these people
يتم تطبيقه الآن عليك كل يوم بواسطة كل هؤلاء الناس
who are Tweeting, blogging, following you,
الذين هم يغردون، يدونون، يتبعونك
watching your credit scores and what you do to yourself.
يشاهدون ارقام الائتمان الخاصة بك، وماذا تقوم به لنفسك.
And electronic tattoos also shout.
و الاوشام الإلكترونية تتحدث أيضا.
And as you're thinking of the consequences of that,
و كما تفكر في عواقب ذلك،
it's getting really hard to hide from this stuff, among other things,
يصبح من الصعب اخفاء هذه الأشياء، من بين أمور أخرى،
because it's not just the electronic tattoos,
لأنه ليس فقط الاوشام الإلكترونية،
it's facial recognition that's getting really good.
ولكن التعرف على الوجه اصبح جيدا.
So you can take a picture with an iPhone and get all the names,
لذا يمكنك التقاط صورة بأي فون والحصول على جميع الأسماء،
although, again, sometimes it does make mistakes. (Laughter)
على الرغم من ذلك، مرة أخرى، في بعض الأحيان قد تحدث الأخطاء. (ضحك)
But that means you can take a typical bar scene like this,
لكن هذا يعني أنه يمكنك أن تأخذ مشهد بار مثل هذا،
take a picture, say, of this guy right here,
تلتقط صورة، مثلا، لهذا الرجل هنا،
get the name, and download all the records
تحصل على الاسم، وتحمل كافة السجلات
before you utter a word or speak to somebody,
قبل أن تنطق بكلمة أو أن تتحدث إلى شخص ما،
because everybody turns out to be
لأن الجميع تبين أنهم
absolutely plastered by electronic tattoos.
ملصقون بأوشام إلكترونية.
And so there's companies like face.com that now have
ولذا يوجد هناك شركات مثل face.com التي لديها الآن
about 18 billion faces online.
حوالي 18 مليار وجه على الإنترنت.
Here's what happened to this company.
هنا ما حدث لهذه الشركة.
[Company sold to Facebook, June 18, 2012...]
[بيعت الشركة للفيسبوك، 18 يونيو 2012...]
There are other companies that will place a camera
وهناك شركات أخرى تضع الكاميرا
like this — this has nothing to do with Facebook —
مثل هذا – وهذا ليس له علاقة بالفيسبوك —
they take your picture, they tie it to the social media,
يلتقطون صورتك، و يربطونها بوسائل التواصل الاجتماعية،
they figure out you really like to wear black dresses,
و يعرفون انك تحبين ارتداء الثياب السوداء،
so maybe the person in the store comes up and says,
لذا ربما الشخص في المتجر يأتي ويقول،
"Hey, we've got five black dresses
"هاي، لدينا خمسة فساتين سوداء
that would just look great on you."
ستبدو رائعة عليك. "
So what if Andy was wrong?
فماذا لو كانت أندي خاطئة؟
Here's Andy's theory.
هنا هي نظرية اندي.
[In the future, everybody will be world famous for 15 minutes.]
[في المستقبل، سيكون الجميع مشاهير العالم لمدة 15 دقيقة.]
What if we flip this?
ماذا لو قلبت هذا؟
What if you're only going to be anonymous for 15 minutes? (Laughter)
ماذا لو كنت فقط مجهولا لمدة 15 دقيقة؟ (ضحك)
Well, then, because of electronic tattoos,
حسنا، بسبب الأوشام الإلكترونية،
maybe all of you and all of us are very close to immortality,
ربما جميعكم و جميعنا، قريبون جدا من الخلود،
because these tattoos will live
بسبب تلك الأوشام التي سوف تعيش
far longer than our bodies will.
وقتاً أطول بكثير من أجسادنا.
And if that's true, then what we want to do
وإذا كان هذا صحيحاً، ما نريد أن نفعله
is we want to go through four lessons from the Greeks
هو أننا نريد أن نتفحص الدروس الأربعة من الإغريق
and one lesson from a Latin American.
ودرسا واحدا من أمريكا اللاتينية.
Why the Greeks?
لماذا الإغريق؟
Well, the Greeks thought about what happens
حسنا، فكر الإغريق حول ما يحدث
when gods and humans and immortality mix for a long time.
عندما تخلط الآلهة والبشر والخلود لفترة طويلة.
So lesson number one: Sisyphus.
لذا الدرس رقم واحد: سيزيف.
Remember? He did a horrible thing, condemned for all time
تذكر؟ أنه عمل شيء فظيع، يشجب في جميع الازمنه
to roll this rock up, it would roll back down,
لدحرجة هذه الصخرة للاعلى، سوف تتدحرج مرة أخرى للاسفل،
roll back up, roll back down.
دحرجة للاعلى، تتدحرج مرة أخرى للاسفل،
It's a little like your reputation.
أنها مثل سمعتك.
Once you get that electronic tattoo,
عندما تحصل على هذا الوشم الإلكتروني،
you're going to be rolling up and down for a long time,
سوف تتدحرج للاعلى و للاسفل لفترة طويلة،
so as you go through this stuff,
لذا عند تجربتك لهذه الأشياء،
just be careful what you post.
فقط كن حذراً لما تنشره.
Myth number two: Orpheus, wonderful guy,
خرافة رقم اثنين: اورفيوس، الرجل الرائع،
charming to be around, great partier, great singer,
مجالسته ساحره، ومغني رائع
loses his beloved, charms his way into the underworld,
يفقد محبوبته، فيكون السحر طريقه الى العالم السفلي،
only person to charm his way into the underworld,
الشخص الوحيد مستخدم السحر للعالم السفلي،
charms the gods of the underworld,
سحر آلهة العالم السفلي،
they release his beauty on the condition
يطلقون محبوبته على شرط
he never look at her until they're out.
أنه ابدأ لا ينظر في وجهها حتى يكونوا في الخارج.
So he's walking out and walking out and walking out
لذا يخرج ويخرج ويخرج
and he just can't resist. He looks at her, loses her forever.
ولم يمكنه أن يقاوم. نظر في وجهها، وفقدها إلى الأبد.
With all this data out here, it might be a good idea
مع كل هذه البيانات هنا، قد تكون فكرة جيدة
not to look too far into the past of those you love.
أن لا ننظر بعيداً جداً في ماضي من تحب.
Lesson number three: Atalanta.
الدرس رقم 3: أتالانتا.
Greatest runner. She would challenge anybody.
عداءة عظيمة. تتحدى أي شخص.
If you won, she would marry you.
إذا فزت، سوف تتزوج بك.
If you lost, you died.
إذا خسرت، تموت.
How did Hippomenes beat her?
كيف فاز هيبومينيس عليها؟
Well, he had all these wonderful little golden apples,
حسنا، كان لديه جميع تلك التفاحات الذهبيه الرائعه،
and she'd run ahead, and he'd roll a little golden apple.
كانت تتعداه، وكان يدحرج تفاحة ذهبية صغيرة.
She kept getting distracted. He eventually won the race.
واصبحت مشتته. وفاز في السباق في نهاية المطاف.
Just remember the purpose as all these little golden apples
فقط تذكر الغرض عندما كل تلك التفاحات الذهبيه
come and reach you and you want to post about them
تأتي اليك وتصلك وأنت ترغب في نشرها
or tweet about them or send a late-night message.
أو كتابة تغريده عنها أو إرسال رسالة في وقت متأخر من الليل.
And then, of course, there's Narcissus.
وبعد ذلك، بطبيعة الحال، هناك ناركيسسوس.
Nobody here would ever be accused or be familiar with Narcissus.
لا أحد هنا يود ان يكون المتهم أو أن تكون على دراية عن ناركيسسوس.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But as you're thinking about Narcissus,
ولكن عندما تفكر في ناركيسسوس،
just don't fall in love with your own reflection.
فقط لا تقع في الحب مع انعكاساتك الخاصة.
Last lesson, from a Latin American:
الدرس الأخير، من أمريكا اللاتينية:
This is the great poet Jorge Luis Borges.
هذا هو الشاعر الكبير خورخي لويس بورخيس.
When he was threatened by the thugs
عندما هدده سفاحو
of the Argentine military junta,
المجلس العسكري الأرجنتيني،
he came back and said, "Oh, come on,
عاد وقال، "أوه، هيا،
how else can you threaten, other than with death?"
كيف يمكن لكم ان تهددوني بشيء خلاف الموت؟ "
The interesting thing, the original thing,
الشيء الجدير بالاهتمام، أن الشيء المبتكر،
would be to threaten somebody with immortality.
سيكون تهديد شخص ما بالخلود.
And that, of course, is what we are all
وهذا، بالطبع، ما نحن جميعا
now threatened with today because of electronic tattoos.
الآن مهددون به اليوم بسبب الاوشام الإلكترونية.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)